(leaves rustling)
Laura:
...years ago.
(indistinct arguing)
Max: That's it!
♪ ♪
(inaudible)
You understand!
I know you do!
Laura:
Ohh!
(poignant violin playing)
(camera shutter clicks)
(vehicle approaching)
Hey, kiddo.
Laura: I feel as if
I've stepped into a,
a time machine.
(dry chuckle)
Oh, my God,
is that a Steenbeck?
Arthur: The perks
of being a drop-out.
I can just do
what I do, my way.
It's nice.
I don't think
in all these years
that I've told you, but...
I'm sorry.
No, Laura,
it was my fault,
not yours.
After what happened,
I needed to leave
the company.
Besides, it was
almost 30 years ago.
I kept up with your work,
you know.
The superheroes in space
with the fourth
dimensional explosions.
New tools.
That's all that is. CGI.
I think you
would have loved it
if you gave it a shot.
I needed something real
to hold on to.
Uh, the service was nice.
Laura, you're here
for a reason, aren't you?
These were always
my favorite.
I don't know
how you do it,
capture a soul
with latex and paint.
Do you think it's possible
to be forgiven by the dead?
Arthur:
No. I tried for 30 years.
The best we can do
is forgive ourselves.
Max and I
were getting divorced.
Well, I haven't spoken
to him for years. I'm sorry.
We were still partners
at work.
We kept the facade,
but at home,
things had gotten
really bad.
On the day he died,
I asked him to come
and see me to talk through
some of the final things
in the divorce agreement.
One thing led to another,
and I...
I started a fight.
It was
the same old fight.
Sing it again.
But this time,
something broke.
He ran outside
from the house,
and he turned
and looked at me
one last time...
and jumped.
Oh, Jesus.
Before he went
over the edge,
his eyes...
Arthur...
I came here
to hire you.
No. No.
(sniffles)
I came here
to beg you.
I need you to make me
one of your maquettes of Max.
I need to look
into his eyes
and beg the forgiveness
of a ghost.
And maybe he'll forgive me
and maybe he won't.
Maybe I'm damned
to follow him over that cliff.
But I need to know.
That's why I'm here.
(kettle whistling)
You can say it.
I've lost it.
I, I must sound nuts.
Grief is
a strange creature.
I just can't let that be
the last time
that I see his face.
I need to apologize.
I need to beg
his forgiveness.
And you're the only one
who can bring him
back for me.
You are the only one
who can understand.
I know you do.
You would do
the same thing.
(classical music playing)
(leaves rustling)
(doorbell rings)
(latch clicks)
Max.
Oh, Max, I'm...
I'm so sorry.
My God, Laura!
My God!
-How could you?
-It was 40 years ago.
If I could undo it,
I would.
But it's done.
We're here and now.
Forget that you saw it.
And let it go.
Max:
Laura, I can't.
I can't lie about this.
I came here to tell you that I'm going
to take the footage to the police.
-Please.
-No!
No, there's no other way.
I've made up my mind.
(Laura sighs)
(kettle whistling)
Okay.
Just...
(whistling continues)
Just hold on.
(pouring tea)
Thank you.
Has, has anyone else
seen the footage?
No one else but me.
I wanted to tell you first
before I went to the police.
I owe you that.
Thank you.
I think you should
tell Arthur. Tonight.
I think he would want
to hear it from you.
Before all this comes out.
Max, you're right.
All of this is right.
And now that
I have accepted it,
it's like a weight has been
lifted from my shoulders.
Thank you for being strong
for both of us.
(soft chuckle)
Max:
I, I can't feel my hands.
What did you do?
It's already
in your system.
In, in a few minutes,
your heart will start to slow.
It will be painless.
Just like falling asleep.
(grunting)
Max, there's nothing
that you can do.
Just let it happen.
You're insane.
The footage is locked
on my drive, Laura.
You can't get to it.
I have all
of your passwords.
I'll delete the file
and burn the original film.
This is everything, Max.
This is everything
that is mine.
And I, I can't let you
take it.
Max! Max!
You understand!
I know you do!
You would do
the same thing.
Look into my eyes, Laura.
Remember this.
Ohh!
Oh, my God.
(dramatic orchestral
music playing)
(sniffles)
(beeps)
Oh shit.
(laughs)
Thank you.
(phone ringing)
MAN: (over phone)
LAM Archives.
Raoul.
How you doing?
It's Laura.
I need you to pull some film for me
and bring it to the house.
It's from the "Dragonfish"
behind-the-scenes shoot
in the '80s.
It's reel number
1-6-6-3-2-4-6.
-Barber: How's the family?
-Man: Doing great.
Johnny's getting
honor roll this semester.
-How's the shop?
-Barber: Never better.
Man:
That's fantastic.
-How's the new job?
-Terrific.
I like my coworkers.
It pays the bills.
-Barber 2: That's wonderful.
-Man 3: Sure.
It's a bit of an adjustment,
but I'm loving married life.
-Barber 4: How's it look?
-Man 4: Great.
Best cut ever.
Oh, my God,
the mountainous volume,
the sheer metric tonnage
of bullshit in this place,
every word,
I swear to God.
I think maybe I'm getting
more sensitive or something.
I'm developing an eye twitch.
Can you see that?
-Yeah.
-Charlie: Yeah.
How do you handle it?
It's a barbershop.
Hey, I need you
to deliver this
to 52 Cherokee.
Old farmhouse
just outside of town.
Extra little for you.
Ah!
-What's in it?
-What do you think?
Right.
In the case
of a one-year-old Yamir.
Charlie:
Not the father.
(doorbell dings)
You are not the father!
(audience cheering)
Every time.
(America's
"Lonely People" playing)
♪ This is for all
the lonely people ♪
♪ Thinking that life
has passed them by ♪
♪ Don't give up until you ♪
♪ Drink from the silver cup ♪
Hello?
♪ And ride that highway
in the sky ♪
Hello.
Got a delivery.
Bag of human hair. Hello.
Jesus.
-Hey.
-Oh.
Oh, hi.
I got your bag of hair
from the, uh,
the barbershop.
Ah, right.
Right.
Right, right. Uh...
Hair.
You're welcome.
Uh... so, uh...
no need
for an explanation.
I, uh...
I'm Charlie, by the way.
Uh, Charlie Cale.
-Arthur.
-Hey, Arthur.
So, uh,
just leave it, uh...
leave it here?
Perfect.
Too easy.
Hey, man, uh, listen,
I'm gettin' the vibe
you want to be left alone,
and, and I really,
I respect that, so I apologize
in advance, but...
well, with the hair
and the, uh...
the monster
in the window,
consider my interest piqued.
So, uh, what do you do?
Charlie, usually,
I, I like to talk
about what I do.
But today, I just buried
an old friend.
So right now,
all I feel like
is getting shitfaced.
My eye's not twitching.
Uh...
which is to say,
that's the first honest thing
I've heard all week.
Uh, and I'm sorry
for your loss.
Hey, listen, I,
I didn't know what kind
of a griever you are,
but if having
some company helps,
I, uh, I'm in no rush
to get back to work.
Sit, leave,
doesn't matter to me.
That blessed honesty.
Gotta say it's
manna from heaven.
Ah!
(soft chuckle)
Mm.
That one stung, Arthur.
(both laugh)
Arthur:
So when I blew smoke out,
it was supposed
to go out the trunk,
it didn't,
it went out the ass.
And it covers the first
three rows of people.
They split.
(laughs)
Everybody else gets out.
Ahh.
Hello.
Art. Jesus.
You are a cool,
cool dude, man.
God, this is
a major relief,
because with the hair
and everything,
I thought maybe you were
potentially some kind
of a serial killer.
Well, if I was
a serial killer,
I wouldn't need hair.
I'd already have hair.
Well, you could be
a serial killer of the bald.
-Aha.
-(Arthur laughs)
Should I call you
a cab?
I got the Cuda.
I got the car.
So I'm all set.
You're not going to drive.
No, no.
To sleep in.
You know, there's a cot
right up there.
You could
crash here tonight.
Oh, that's not scary at all.
That's great.
Yeah.
Jesus.
Monsters,
monsters, monsters.
Wow, wow.
Holy cow.
All this comes
from inside your head?
I mean, it must be
a horror show in there.
Hell, you got
no idea, kid.
Monsters.
Screams from the void.
Void screams?
-Yeah.
-Very heavy.
Alright,
So I'm standing
and I'm looking
and I'm thinking.
And so, feel free
to say it's a no-go,
but do you need
an assistant?
Now, before you answer that,
I should warn you
that I only accept cash,
and you can feel free
to underpay me.
Well...
why not?
Welcome to
the House of Horrors,
Charlie Cale.
Alright.
(dramatic music playing)
Mamma mia.
Don't touch those.
Oh. Yeah, sorry, I just,
I see you working on it
all the time, I got curious.
So, uh, what's it, uh,
what's it going to be?
I'm calling it
The Orpheus Syndrome.
Oh yeah?
What's it about?
It's a non-narrative.
Oh, uh, you want some
of this jelly toast?
-It's freaking delicious.
-You bought jelly?
Mm, no. It's, uh, you had some
of it in your fridge.
You know,
that's fake blood.
Do you know how
expensive that stuff is?
That costs more
than real blood.
Arterialicious.
Oh shit.
-Fuck, Arthur. I'm sorry.
-No, no, no.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of that.
-You hang this...
-Yeah. Okay.
...on the film bin.
Charlie:
I'm sorry.
Arthur:
That's alright.
(vehicle approaching)
Laura: Arthur,
I need you to make me
one of your maquettes
of Max.
I need to look
into his eyes
and beg forgiveness
from a ghost.
And maybe he'll forgive me
and maybe he won't.
Maybe I'm damned to follow him
over that cliff.
But I need to know.
That's why I'm here.
(kettle whistling)
Are you okay?
We got a new job.
I'm going to need
you full time
for a few weeks.
(sighs)
Hey, uh, look, uh...
I know this is weird,
but, uh, whatever
that lady asked you for,
whatever she told you
she was here for,
she wasn't.
Okay?
She was lying.
I could tell.
Oh.
Snoop.
(chuckles)
I, I don't know
what lies mean
when you're
that deep in grief.
She's a friend.
I gonna help her.
Let's get to work.
So to help
your friend,
we're building a model
of your dead friend's head.
Twisted web.
So this is Max, huh?
And, uh, what's her name?
Laura.
Those were the good years,
the early years.
What happened? Why did you stop
working with them?
Pair of monsters
or what?
No, it wasn't that.
Well, what was it?
It was my fault.
It was supposed to be
my big debut as a director.
Creature feature,
"Black Lagoon"-style.
And we had a terrific
young actress,
Lily Albern.
She died on the set.
And, and it all died
that day.
Christ, Arthur, fuck.
It was an accident.
We were shooting a scene
where she went underwater
and the sea monster
attacked her.
We had a big tank set up
with an emergency system.
If she had an issue
in the tank,
she would hit a button
and this red
emergency light bulb
would go off,
and we'd cut
and pull her out.
Eyebrows.
It was a crazy day.
We were running behind,
and Lily was having
trouble in the tank.
She'd go in, and the red light
would go on.
We would cut
and pull her out.
Over and over again.
I got frustrated.
Everybody was.
And then on the last take,
everything went perfect.
The sea monster attacked her.
She thrashed.
She struggled.
We got it.
So we were elated.
But...
she wasn't moving.
And when we pulled her
out of the tank...
she was dead.
Fuck.
Why didn't she, uh,
set off the red light bulb?
Arthur:
I don't know.
I, I, I can't believe
that it was
because I was frustrated
with her
and she didn't want
to let me down.
But...
I do believe that.
I believe that...
I killed her.
So that's why you
walked away from all this?
You better believe it.
I, uh,
I lost a friend.
She was my best friend,
uh, Natalie.
And, uh, you know, I wonder
if I could have saved her,
but I didn't.
And so
I walked away too.
You know, I keep thinking
it's behind me, right?
But then I keep just, like,
playing it back out again,
trying to,
trying to make it right,
trying to change it.
I don't know.
I mean,
does it ever end?
Do I believe that
the dead can forgive us?
No, I don't believe that.
Bullshit.
-What?
-I mean, if you didn't think
the dead could forgive us,
you wouldn't be making
your whole movie,
the, uh,
"The Orpheus Syndrome."
I mean, that's what
it's all about.
Bringing the past back to life
like a ritual of penitence.
Arthur:
Ritual of penitence?
Who appointed you Pope?
I was recently anointed.
Thank you.
I, uh... come on, man.
Cut the shit.
I mean, you got Orpheus
who's going
through film gates
into the underworld,
which looks like a water tank
to bring a girl
back from the dead.
The guy's got
a movie camera for a face.
The other guy,
that Cyclops monster,
he's got a red
light bulb for an eye.
I mean, I'm not judging.
Just, you know,
it all makes sense.
You got to revisit the past
to get past it, huh?
You think that's true?
Hey, dominae vomingus dingus.
I'm gonna make
some Hot Pockets.
-You want some?
-Yeah.
Alright, Arthur.
-It's cool.
-Yeah?
Yeah.
(phone ringing)
(mumbling)
LAM Archives.
They still got you
in the basement, huh?
(Raoul laughs)
Arthur.
Haven't heard
your voice
in such a long time.
How are you, my friend?
Arthur:
Uh, I'm fine.
I need you to do a favor.
I need you to pull
some footage for me.
Reel numbers 1-6-6-3-2-3-4
through 1-6-6-3-2-4-6.
That was everything
on April the 12th, 1989.
Are you sure?
-That's, um...
-Arthur: I know.
I know what's on there.
I'm not supposed
to check anything out.
But that's okay, buddy.
Um...
Max was digitizing everything
for the 40th anniversary.
He got through that pile
of stuff already.
Nobody's going to miss it.
Thank you, old friend.
Raoul: I'll bring 'em
over tomorrow.
Yeah.
Hey, I'm Raoul.
Um, I'm here to deliver
some film to Arthur.
Is he around?
That's terrific.
He's inside.
I'm, uh, I'm Charlie,
his, uh, assistant
and head deliverer.
You're the head
of delivery.
No, I, uh,
I deliver heads.
-Alright.
-Alright. Cool.
Yeah, he's right in there.
Okay. Thank you.
I like your car.
I like the Honda.
It's my mother's car.
It's okay.
Ah geez.
Nice patch of concrete
too much to ask for,
I guess.
(grunts)
(organ music playing)
That was it.
Young Arthur:
Jesus fucking Christ!
Are you fucking
kidding me?
-Lily: I can't do it.
-Young Arthur: You can do this.
We need you
to do this, honey.
This is what
you're being paid for.
Lily:
This isn't safe.
♪ ♪
(clicking)
(tape rewinding)
(stops tape)
Laura:
Raoul.
How you doing?
It's Laura.
I need you to pull
some film for me
and bring it
to the house.
It's from
the "Dragonfish"
behind-the-scenes shoot
in the '80s.
It's reel number 1-6-6-3-2-4-6.
Raoul: I'm sorry.
I don't have it.
Wha--Uh, what?
What do you mean?
It's with the rest of
the "Dragonfish" footage.
I don't have any of it.
I checked it out.
What the fuck,
checked it out.
What are we,
a lending library?
To whom
did you check it out?
Raoul:
Sorry, Laura.
Arthur has it.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna
call him right now,
and I'm going
to go over there,
-and I'm going to...
-(doorbell rings)
Raoul:
...to go get it for you.
Don't worry
about it, Raoul.
Forget I ever called.
Raoul: Please,
don't be mad at me.
I've spent
my whole life thinking
that I killed that girl.
I'm sorry.
If I had thought...
I never would have.
I'd never.
I thought she was being...
I don't even know,
an actress,
a silly actress.
And we had put everything
into that production.
Our houses.
All of us.
And we were bleeding money.
I shielded you, too.
You didn't even know
how in the hole we were,
every day we went over.
Arthur,
it was an accident.
Raoul said that
Max had digitized
these reels.
Did Max see this?
Did he tell you
he saw it?
I am so sorry
that you held this
for all these years.
But I did, too.
I did it and I held it
so you boy geniuses
could make your monsters
and not have to wonder
what it all cost.
I was doing the dirty work,
always, for both of you.
And you can pretend
that you didn't see it,
but don't you fucking
judge me for it.
I move forward.
Always forward.
And I am not going
to lose what I built.
And you're right that the dead
can't forgive me...
but they also
can't hurt me.
Laura, let me ask you this.
Did you have anything
to do with Max's death?
He jumped
right in front of me,
like he wanted
to punish me.
My hand to God.
No one will see
this footage.
Thank you.
Arthur, I am so sorry.
(sighs)
(laughs)
Oh.
(tires squealing)
Oh, he wouldn't.
Charlie:
Arthur!
Arthur. Arthur.
Woman: (over phone) Stay calm, ma'am.
The police will be there shortly.
Can I get your name
and information?
Would you just,
just send somebody quick?
Okay? Please.
Shit.
Arthur, man.
I'm sorry,
I gotta go, okay.
Alright.
What the fuck?
(engine starts)
Laura:
Oh, his heart was always...
He always had trouble
with his heart.
I'm just happy
he didn't suffer.
I'm calling with
a legal question.
LAM funded Arthur's work.
I'm, I'm wondering
when we can get possession
of his workshop.
Well, today, if we can.
I'd like to see what's there
and pull some pieces
for our 40th anniversary
celebration tonight.
As a tribute.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
Okay. Well, work at it
and call me back.
Excuse me.
-Charlie: Hi.
-May I help you?
Charlie:
I was, uh...
Hi.
Laura, right?
I'm Charlie.
I was, uh...
I was Arthur's assistant.
I dropped off the head.
Right.
How may I help you?
Uh...
Well, gee, this is,
this is sort of weird.
I thought I'd know how
to put it when I got here,
but it was so sudden,
his death.
And, uh, well, I'd gotten
kind of close to him.
Like, I really cared
about the guy.
Anyway...
he never left the house.
Like, literally
never went anywhere.
But I think
maybe the day he died,
he came to see you.
Ah, gosh,
I, I'm sorry.
You know what?
I feel really intrusive here.
Maybe I shouldn't have come.
I shouldn't have come.
I'm sorry.
No, I get it.
It's, it's alright.
Why don't you come inside?
-Thanks.
-Laura: My mother had
a framed
embroidery thing
over our commode
growing up
that said
"Strange Blessings."
And that's what yesterday
made me think of.
I didn't expect him,
and he just showed up
out of the blue.
And I'm so glad he did,
that I, I got to say
goodbye to him,
see him one last time.
Strange blessings.
God. But he wanted
to talk about the past.
About Max.
All of it.
I'm sorry.
And if I'm overstepping, please.
But, uh, do you feel
like in talking
and whatever you guys said,
that maybe he reconciled
his guilt?
Look, I don't know
what I'm asking. I...
Maybe I just want to know
if he got some peace
in the end.
Peace?
I don't know.
Peace, that's, that's
many different things,
but I, I think...
No. I know that he was,
he was able to let go
of blaming himself
for Lily's death.
Does that help you?
Oh yeah. That's...
that's, wow.
That's, uh, albatross.
Over here.
Thank you. I, uh...
Geez. Uh, thanks.
(scoffs) I...
And look, uh,
I'm sorry to show up
and bother you.
No. It feels good to give
someone else some comfort.
Arthur gave me that too
with his maquettes
and our conversation.
That's great.
Yeah, it really did help me.
Yeah. Well, I bet. I bet.
How could it not?
Oh.
Helped me to say
goodbye to him
and feel
some kind of release
that I wasn't responsible
for Max's death.
Uh, thank you so much
for coming by.
It's really great to meet you.
Take care, Charlie.
Charlie:
Uh...
You said
you weren't responsible?
What?
Uh, could you repeat
what you said before.
I think
my hearing is going.
That I wasn't responsible
for Max's death?
And that like Arthur
had to let go,
I have to do the same.
Max's death wasn't
my fault.
And Arthur's heart problem
just caught up with him.
Neither were a result
of my actions.
I didn't kill them.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Well, goodbye, Charlie.
I hope I've given you
some peace.
(sighs)
What?
Hey, Head Delivery.
No, she killed both of them,
okay. She basically told me.
Not even basically,
she just told me.
I mean, not directly,
but, you know,
she was lying,
and I could tell she was lying, so.
What is this,
a woman's intuition?
No, it's not like
a tampon commercial, okay.
It's a real thing.
It's no big deal,
but I can detect lies.
Wait, what are you
doing here?
Oh, Arthur, he checked out
some film,
and then Laura
requested the same reel,
so I'm in some deep shit.
-And I gotta get it back.
-What?
Yeah, I know.
Weird coincidence.
I mean, nobody's looked
at this stuff for years.
Coincidence, my foot.
Okay, so let me
get this straight.
You dropped
the film off to Arthur.
I went to drop
the head off to Laura.
He was watching the film.
Then when I got back from Laura's,
he had gone there.
So whatever he saw
on that film
made him go
to Laura's, yeah?
Okay.
What's on those reels?
It's behind the scenes
of the "Dragonfish" set
the day Lily died.
-Oh shit.
-Yeah, I thought it was pretty dark.
He wanted to see it,
but he was going
through some shit.
Yeah. Got to face
the past to get past it.
(scoffs)
Alright, man.
Well, we got
to watch that stuff.
We got to see
what he saw.
How does this thing work?
Is it like a VCR?
-Hold on. Laptop, please.
-Yeah.
Laptop.
(claps)
Okay. Here, Max was digitizing
the entire archives.
I think I could get a copy
from our cloud drive.
Double-Oh face scan, Batman.
Yeah, I know.
Yeah.
Security's nuts. Okay.
Good, good.
Uh, let's, uh,
let's start
with this one, 2-4-6.
-Two-four-six. Two-four-six.
-Okay.
Hmm. That's weird.
The files showed up
for the reels
245 and 247 but no 246.
-Max.
-What?
So if Max had this
on his files,
you'd need his face, right?
Okay, so, Laura, used the maquette
to access the files
and, uh, delete it.
She what?
B-b-but...
Wait a second,
we have the original film.
Oh God.
Shit, man.
Arthur was killed for whatever
was on that reel of film.
Look, we got
to find it before--
(vehicle approaching)
Hide!
All this stuff goes to LAM,
but bag up
the loose film separately.
I'll take care
of that myself.
-I want every bit of film.
-Man: Yes, ma'am.
Don't leave
a scrap behind.
Man: You got it.
Alright.
Whoever you are,
come out, come out.
I can smell
your Hot Pockets.
Come on, fanboy.
Out!
Raoul.
-What's that?
-You tell me.
Arthur brought that reel of film
to my house last night
and burned it.
True. Shit.
He burned it.
It was all destroyed.
-Bullshit.
-Laura: And I don't know
what you think
is going on here,
but this is over.
So go get back
in your fucking basement!
♪ ♪
Hurry up!
What are you looking for?
I want every last piece of it.
Don't miss a single
loose scrap of film.
I want it all bagged up.
It's going to me.
He spliced it out.
Man: Yeah, I'll take
the Medusa head next.
Man 2:
Need help with that?
Charlie:
There it is.
Laura:
That's great.
I, I also want
to have a, a tribute
to Arthur tonight.
All the maquettes
from his workshop,
from my home,
from the office,
I want a whole room
dedicated to him
and to the film
that he never got to finish.
Well, I'll be there in an hour.
Get it done.
This evening
is going to belong
to Arthur and Max.
(operatic music playing)
(beeps)
Laura wants all this stuff
-up on the second floor.
-Yeah, yeah.
Okay? And we don't have much time.
We're already running late.
Why are you carrying it
like a baby?
Man:
He's fragile.
Charlie:
Oh, fuck my life.
Woman: ...gone in, like,
five minutes upstairs.
Man:
You're not Laura.
Woman: Okay, but I'm
speaking for Laura.
♪ ♪
(indistinct chatter)
So pretty much, uh...
Can you please
hold on a minute?
Thank you.
What's going on?
It's company policy
that nothing leaves
the archives.
You violated that policy,
so I'm afraid we're going
to have to let you go.
Are you serious, Laura?
It's company policy.
It's me.
Hey, look me
in the eyes, Laura.
Laura, what is wrong
with you?
(chatter on radio)
Security will escort
you out.
Um, we have a problem.
There's a horse loose
on the premises.
(dramatic music playing)
♪ ♪
Charlie: Where are you,
witchy woman?
Where are you,
Not here.
Medusa?
No, not Medusa. Shit.
Ah? Oh, yes!
Laura:
There it is.
Charlie:
Oh shit.
Horse, who are you?
Charlie:
Oh.
Hi.
Okay. Uh, alright,
alright, alright.
I'm sorry. This thing is not designed
for quick removal.
Escort her off the premises.
And if she steps one hoof
on this property again,
have her arrested.
Man:
Oh, my God, look.
Look, that's the horse
from "Caligula's Revenge."
That's so cool.
Amazing.
Raoul:
Charlie?
Raoul. Hey.
Okay. I'm not even
going to ask.
Oh, it's my purse.
Uh, listen,
So I found the film.
Okay. Check it out.
He spliced part of it out.
And then he hid it
in one of his monsters
in the, uh,
in the snake hair.
The Medusa from
"Zazamoosh."
Yes. Yeah,
the Medusa from that.
Shit, wait.
Is that one of those sad
"you're fired" boxes?
Yeah. You know,
40 years, man.
She couldn't even look me
in the eye when she did it.
Shit, man. I'm sorry,
that's--
I was sick
of that basement,
and I guess
she was a murderer.
So time was right.
Hey, uh,
you think your, uh,
keycard is turned off yet?
-(audience applauds)
-Laura: Thank you, everyone.
We are so glad
that you are here.
Tonight is bittersweet.
I never expected
to be celebrating
without Arthur
and Max by my side.
Charlie: Okay. It's now
or never, right?
-Raoul: Oh no. It's going to be now.
-Charlie: Okay.
Laura: I know that
if they were here tonight,
they would be so happy...
about what I have done
to keep this company alive.
Or at the very least,
they would understand.
I, I hope that they
would understand
why I did what I did.
Ooh.
(gasps)
(audience murmuring)
I'm sorry. I...
Very funny.
As we look back
on our history...
there are so many moments
to be proud of.
The--When Lily died
on the set of "Dragonfish,"
I thought it would
end us forever.
But... tonight,
we put the past behind us
once and for all!
(audience murmuring)
What I mean is
the past cannot...
-Charlie: Sorry.
-Raoul: Excuse me.
The past, uh, cannot...
hurt us.
I, um...
I'm, this is...
I have to go...
Just...
play it.
(ominous music playing)
(growling)
(roaring)
Narrator:
LAM began
as a humble
practical effects shop
conceived by three
Cal Arts animation students
in 1975.
Arthur, Max, and Laura
founded the company
on one simple idea,
that imagination
could be made real.
This collective
childhood love of monsters
is what inspired them
to build LAM.
Throughout the years,
this powerful trio
have set the standard
for monster creation.
And in order
to feel real,
it has to be real.
We see, uh, creation
of life from clay
not only in the Bible,
but in every ancient mythology
around the world.
When I'm in my studio...
(projector clicking)
...I am bringing
things to life.
And there's just
no other feeling--
Laura:
Stop it! Shut it off.
-(audience murmuring)
-Young Arthur: You feel like...
Shut it off!
Young Arthur:
...you're divine.
(audience murmuring)
Shut it off.
Stop it!
(ominous music playing)
(growling)
♪ ♪
Oh...
Max.
Max?
Max!
Look into my eyes, Laura.
Remember this.
No!
(projector clicking)
(body thuds)
-Hey.
-Raoul: Charlie.
Oh fuck.
(orchestral music playing)